<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Zander Mackie</title>
    <link>zmackie.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Zander Mackie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 12:33:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="zmackie.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What even is a container</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/what-even-is-a-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 12:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/what-even-is-a-container/</guid>
      <description>Cgroups
Namespaces
Seccomp
Etc
OCI image format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give a damn</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/give-a-damn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 18:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/give-a-damn/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, at the very end, I alluded to a Docker cli gotcha. For those of you who didn&#39;t have a shudder of recognition, I&#39;ll tell you something it took me a while to figure out: docker run koolKontainer:latest /bin/bash does not update your local copy of the image with that tag. You must docker pull koolKontainer:latest to make sure your image is up to date.
In other words, if you have an old copy of that image, tagged with latest, the former command will run that old local copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joys of debugging</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/the-joys-of-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 21:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/the-joys-of-debugging/</guid>
      <description>Today at work I was trying to merging a PR, and I noticed something very strange during the rebase. I work on a team that, among other things, manages dependencies for applications [https://github.com/buildpack]. We define the versions of a runtime available to an application through a manifest, which is in YAML form. And part of the manifest includes SHAs of the runtimes, which we use to verify their integrity.
A select few of SHAs now had single quotes around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Learning How to Learn&#39;</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 11:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Learning how to learn&amp;rsquo;, by Barbara Oakley, is a compendium of techniques for learning effectively or more effectively, backed by neuroscience and cognitive psychology. Increasing ones ability to learn speeds up your knowledge compounding rate, and is time magnificently well spent.
 Know of and take advantage of the different modes of the brain: Diffuse and Focussed. If you&#39;re learning something totally new or you&#39;re stuck on a problem, take a break of some sort to allow diffuse mode to do its work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am security and so can you</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/i-am-security-and-so-can-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 17:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/i-am-security-and-so-can-you/</guid>
      <description>Security, from the perspective of a programmer, often feels abstract. It&#39;s both a domain of knowledge and a quality of the programs we write and the systems we construct. And given that, how does one approach learning security? How do we know if our code is insecure? How can we make our code more secure? Its not something you can easily measure, and the scope and scales of it boggle the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wisdom of Cliff Stoll</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/the-wisdom-of-cliff-stoll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 17:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/the-wisdom-of-cliff-stoll/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working hard to be lazy</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/working-hard-to-be-lazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 12:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/working-hard-to-be-lazy/</guid>
      <description>So that&#39;s a picture of a great writer, UKLG. She&#39;s completely not lazy, so apologies to her for inclusion. She&#39;s here, though, because she invented something great: The ansible 🌌. And why is that relevant? We&#39;ll get there&amp;hellip;
As any smart human person in charge of configuring and managing computers knows, I&#39;m bad at my job. Or rather, my job is nearly impossible to be good at, given my human limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzing Open VNC</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/fuzzing-open-vnc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/fuzzing-open-vnc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff you might want to learn if...</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/stuff-you-might-want-to-learn-if.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 16:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/stuff-you-might-want-to-learn-if.../</guid>
      <description>** ..you work with computers: How your brain works How to make decisions How to learn [https://www.coursera.org/learn/learning-how-to-learn] How to be effective [https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QXN35r2_20s] Good things other people have already figured out
** ..you work with other people in technology
How computers work:
 From nand to tetris (book + coursera) Computer systems: a programmers perspective GDB: https://beej.us/guide/bggdb/ Assembly vidoes: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLmxT2pVYo5LB5EzTPZGfFN0c2GDiSXgQe  Networking:
 TCP/IP illustrated, vol. 1 Some videos wireshark  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraints</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 01:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/constraints/</guid>
      <description>Artists are famously driven by cons</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 01:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m Zander Mackie. I work in tech, on cloud stuff and security, but I&#39;m more interested in people and bugs than bits. I want to be Dan Geer when I grow up.
In past lives, I studied music with monks in mountains, crafted cave-aged cheese, and edited evil advertisments. You could say I&#39;ve seen a lot. I don&#39;t know if I&#39;m old, wise, and sad yet, but I&#39;ve got some grey hairs to prove it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Problems</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/important-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/important-problems/</guid>
      <description>Richard Hamming asked the chemists in the Bell Labs Cafeteria:
What are the most important problems in your field? And why aren&#39;t you working on them?
The ever brilliant Haroon Meer got me thinking about this question recently; what are the important problems these days? And why aren&#39;t I working on them?
In technology, so much seems driven by the market, advertising, and hype. I suppose that&#39;s better than war being the engine, but it somehow seems hollow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I learned how to learn how to code</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/how-i-learned-how-to-learn-how-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 23:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/how-i-learned-how-to-learn-how-to-code/</guid>
      <description>I was reading the Turing Omnibus, doing some research into error correction, and I learned about Hamming Codes. I might have understood the concept at the time, but today, what I remember is the offhand comment my friend made about their creator, Richard Hamming.
Oh you should watch his talk &amp;ldquo;You and Your Research&amp;rdquo;
At this point in my life, I&#39;d been laid off form my first startup and was taking a break to &amp;ldquo;get better at programming&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night &amp; Day</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/night-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 23:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/night-day/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s open with a cliche: What a difference a day makes.[1]
Yesterday was Friday. An RC batch runs M-Th for &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; days, reserving Fridays for prepping for interviews and job related stuff. The point is to bracket that time and that stress so the rest of the week we focus on programming, not job hunting. That&#39;s smart. Another example of removing the barriers to improvement.
Yesterday we did a practice interview project: spend 3 hours building a link shortener ala bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limits</title>
      <link>zmackie.com/posts/limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 23:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zmackie.com/posts/limits/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m afraid to publish this post[1], but naming things can often kill their power over you, as Ged learned of his shadow. And so it is with some trepidation that I bring you the following story:
One of my goals at RC was to blog every day I was there. I kept this going for a good while, but I recently fell down. For the last two weeks it&#39;s been radio silence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>